Expect The Savage. The Sensual. The Shocking. The Sad. The
Powerful. The Shameful. Expect The Truth.
Mandingo is a romance, drama, history film directed by Richard Fleischer.
Warren Maxwell, the owner of a run-down plantation, pressures his son,
Hammond, to marry and produce an heir to inherit the plantation.
Hammond settles on his own cousin, Blanche, but purchases a
sex slave when he returns from the honeymoon.
He also buys his father a new Mandingo slave named Mede
to breed and train as a prize-fighter.
Hammond Maxwell, played by Perry King.
Warren Maxwell, played by James Mason.
Blanche Woodford Maxwell, played by Susan George.
Mede (Ganymede), played by Ken Norton.
Agamemnon, played by Richard Ward.
Ellen, played by Brenda Sykes.
Mandingo is a 1975 American historical melodrama film focusing on
the Atlantic slave trade in the Antebellum South.
The film's title refers to the Mandinka people, who are referred to as
"Mandingos", and described as being good slaves for fighting matches.
The word is also used as a pejorative to describe a hypersexual Black man.
Produced by Dino De Laurentiis for Paramount Pictures, the
film was directed by Richard Fleischer.
The screenplay, by Norman Wexler, was adapted from the 1957 novel Mandingo by Kyle Onstott,
and the 1961 play Mandingo by Jack Kirkland (which is derived from the novel).
The film stars Perry King as Hammond, the son of cruel
slave owner Warren Maxwell (James Mason).
Hammond is known to have sex with female slaves on his father's plantation, and his father
orders him to marry a white woman to produce grandchildren with no black ancestry.
Hammond marries Blanche (Susan George), his cousin, who becomes jealous that he pays more attention to his black lover Ellen (Brenda Sykes)
than to his wife, leading Blanche to force the Mandingo fighting slave Mede (Ken Norton) into a sexual relationship with her.
Mandingo received negative reviews upon release.
However, retrospectively, the film's reception became much more favorable.
It has been variously seen as a big-budget exploitation film made by a major studio, a serious film about American
slavery, examining historical horrors committed against African Americans, or as a work of camp.
It was a box office hit, and was followed by a sequel, Drum (1976), which
starred Norton as a different character and Warren Oates as Hammond.
The film explores themes of bare knuckle boxing, slavery,
interracial relationship, slave owner.
The tone is emotional.